Jingeon.
Jingeon.
I told you to stay out of this!
¡Te dije que no te metieras!
You're...
Está…
Yes. Do you get it now?
Sí, ¿lo entiendes ahora?
Do you remember who you killed?
¿Recuerdas a quién mataste?
Do you now realize what your sin is?
¿Recuerdas tu pecado?
What does that mean?
¿Qué pasó aquí?
There's one more thing that annoys me.
Hay algo más que me molesta,
It's the thought of you hanging out with him,
y es que te juntes con él aunque sepas quién es en verdad.
Explain?
¿Explicar?
Did you know about him?
¿Sabías de él?
-Know what? -This guy's identity.
- ¿Saber qué? - Quién es en verdad.
No way.
No puede ser.
I thought I was mistaken.
Creí que estaba equivocaba.
What do you mean by that?
¿Qué quieres decir?
Whom did he kill?
¿A quién mató?
Is it Momyeong?
¿A Momyeong?
Did he kill Momyeong?
¿Mató a Momyeong?
It's childish, but I thought I should give him a chance.
Le quise dar una oportunidad,
Although nothing would've changed even with a proper answer.
aunque ninguna respuesta hubiera cambiado las cosas.
You said you only tell the truth.
Dijiste que no mientes.
I don't lie.
No miento.
I'm not immature.
No soy inmaduro.
I only speak the truth.
Solo digo la verdad.
For the past 1,200 years,
Por los últimos 1200 años, he imaginado matarte miles de veces.
You probably have no idea how much I wanted our powers to be swapped.
No sabes cuánto quise intercambiar nuestros poderes.
You had to live through the endless vicious cycle
de que tuviste que sufrir por miles de años en esa cueva.
The thought of you rotting like that...
Imaginarte sufriendo en esa cueva
made me realize that it's probably the sweetest revenge.
fue la mejor venganza que pude pedir.
But...
Pero aún así,
you get to see the sun and breathe like this?
¿puedes ver el sol y respirar aire puro?
How dare you breathe and smile?
¿Cómo te atreves?
Stop it.
Para.
That's enough.
Es suficiente.
He's not picking up.
No contesta.
When did he meet him for the first time?
¿Dónde lo habrá conocido?
And what? For the past 1,200 years?
¿Hace 1200 años?
Also, the cave. What does that mean?
¿Y a qué cueva se refiere?
Do you think Jingeon will be okay?
¿Crees que se salve?
I think he stopped his power in the middle of it.
Detuvo su poder a último momento.
Had he used it fully, it would've been very bad.
Hubiera sido muy malo de no haber sido así.
And who's Momyeong?
¿Quién es Momyeong?
You don't know him?
¿No lo conoces?
His twin brother.
Su gemelo. Era como la sombra de Biryeom.
Biryeom was so fond of him.
Biryeom le tenía mucho cariño.
At some point, I realized that he was nowhere to be seen.
Desapareció en algún momento.
I had no idea that was what happened.
No sabía que había pasado eso.
I should've paid more attention.
Debí prestar más atención.
Don't feel guilty.
No te sientas culpable.
You've always been indifferent toward Biryeom.
Siempre has sido indiferente con Biryeom.
Why didn't he tell me, though?
Pero ¿por qué no me contó?
Can't you see that I can't tell you because it's you?
No puedo contarte porque eres tú
Because you're the one asking me for an explanation...
la que me lo está preguntando.
Why...
¿Por qué?
Why did he...
¿Por qué mató
-kill Momyeong? -I don't know.
- a Momyeong? - No lo sé.
I'm very disappointed in Mr. Shin.
Estoy muy decepcionada con el señor Shin.
You gods think of yourselves as saviors.
Ustedes los dioses se creen salvadores.
But what can you do to me?
Pero ¿qué harán conmigo? ¿Planean matarme o qué?
Can you do...
¿Puedes hacer
a better job in doing that than I can?
un mejor trabajo que yo?
For the past 1,200 years,
Los últimos 1200 años,
I've killed you in my head countless times.
he imaginado matarte miles de veces.
You had to live through the endless vicious cycle of
Tuviste que sufrir por miles de años en esa cueva.
The thought of you rotting like that
Imaginarte sufriendo en esa cueva
made me realize that it's probably the sweetest revenge.
fue la mejor venganza que pude pedir.
But...
Pero aún así,
you get to see the sun and breathe like this?
¿puedes ver el sol y respirar aire puro?
How dare you breathe and smile?
¿Cómo te atreves?
MR. SHIN HU-YE
SR. SHIN HU-YE
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
Biryeom pulled a prank.
Biryeom estaba bromeando.
-He'll sort it out with his-- -He's like you guys, isn't he?
- Va a… - Es como ustedes, ¿no?
I'm talking about Mr. Shin.
El señor Shin.
He's from your world, isn't he?
Es de tu mundo, ¿no?
-Why didn't you tell me? -Did I have to tell you?
- ¿Por qué no me contaste? - ¿Debía hacerlo?
-Sorry? -You never asked.
- ¿Qué? - Nunca preguntaste.
He's not like us.
No es como nosotros.
But...
Pero…
It must've been you guys.
Deben ser ustedes.
-What? -I'm sure of it.
- ¿Qué? - Estoy segura.
Those who told Mr. Shin that he shouldn't have been born.
Le dijeron que no debió haber nacido.
Since when...
¿Desde cuándo
were you two close enough to talk about such things?
son tan cercanos para hablar de eso?
Why did you say that?
¿Por qué le dijeron eso? ¿Por qué lo criticaron así?
You guys are gods. Gods should--
Son dioses. Deberían…
Did it start after I left?
¿Empezó cuando me fui?
Or was it before that?
¿O antes de eso?
Were you hoping that I'd leave?
¿Esperabas que me fuera?
You said you're lesser...
Dijiste que eras una luchadora porque aguantas todo.
But...
Pero ¿lloraste como una perdedora?
Is that why you opened up to him so quickly?
¿Por eso confiaste en él tan rápido?
Why are you being like this?
- ¿Por qué te pones así? - ¿No te lo dije?
I told you to bear in mind
Te dije que tuvieras en cuenta
that I can be very jealous of your male friends
que puedo ser muy celoso de tus amigos
and that I'm not rational.
y que no soy racional.
When did he meet him for the first time?
¿Dónde lo habrá conocido?
And what? For the past 1,200 years?
¿Hace 1200 años?
Also, the cave. What does that mean?
¿Y a qué cueva se refiere?
Nak-bin is hiding in the Land of the Sky.
Nak-bin está en la Nación del Cielo,
I heard she is in one of the caves that the King owns.
oculta en una de las cuevas del rey.
-Can you ask around? -It won't make any difference.
- ¿Puedes revisar? - No hará diferencia.
No place in the divine realm would be safe for her.
No hay lugar seguro para ella en el reino divino
The same goes for the human world.
ni en el mundo humano.
I'm not trying to rescue her.
No quiero rescatarla.
And I'll never forgive her.
Nunca la perdonaré.
It's just there's something I want to know.
Solo quiero saber algo.
What do you want to know?
¿Qué cosa?
I want to ask her...
Quiero preguntarle
what I was to her.
qué fui para ella.
That can't be.
No puede ser.
-Hey, Yeom-mi. -What is it now?
- Yeom-mi. - ¿Qué pasa ahora?
Well...
Bueno, digamos que hay alguien llamado A.
Go on.
Sigue.
Why would A suddenly overreact and get upset during a conversation?
¿Por qué se enojaría durante una conversación?
-Break up with him. -What?
- Termina con él. - ¿Qué?
I'm sure A is a guy.
Seguro que A es un hombre.
What?
¿Qué?
-Yes. -He must have anger management issues.
- Sí. - ¿Tiene problemas de ira?
Gosh. No, he doesn't.
Cielos, no.
Then he's just a jerk.
Entonces es un imbécil.
-No, he isn't. Not at all. -He feels guilty about something.
- No lo es. Para nada. - Siente culpa por algo.
-What? -Guys are like that.
- ¿Qué? - Así son los hombres.
When they realize that they did something wrong, they get angry.
Cuando se dan cuenta de que hicieron algo malo, se enojan.
That's how they test women's patience.
Así ponen a prueba tu paciencia.
Break up with him.
¡Termina con él!
-Hello. -Dr. Yun, this is Mr. Min.
- ¿Aló? - Dra. Yun, soy es el señor Min.
-Oh, hello. -Have you heard from Mr. Shin at all?
Sí, hola.
No. He's not at work yet?
No, ¿no está en su trabajo?
I see. All right.
No, aún no llega.
Please call me if you hear anything from him.
Avíseme si sabe algo de él.
Okay, I will.
Está bien.
MR. SHIN HU-YE
SR. SHIN HU-YE
DR. YUN SO-A
DRA. YUN SO-A
I've found Biryeom.
Encontré a Biryeom.
Tell me.
Cuéntame.
That day,
Ese día,
you went to that cave, didn't you?
¿fuiste a la cueva?
Did you...
¿Acaso
meet that guy there?
lo conociste ahí?
Is that...
¿Fue ahí
when Momyeong died?
que murió Momyeong?
Why didn't you tell me?
¿Por qué no me contaste?
You said you weren't there.
Dijiste que no fuiste ahí.
You said you wouldn't help me.
Dijiste que no me ayudarías.
I've thought about it, but I can't help you.
Lo consideré, pero no puedo ayudarte.
I mean, I don't want to.
Es decir, no quiero ayudarte.
You broke Mura's heart.
Le rompiste el corazón a Mura.
You don't deserve to be happy.
No mereces ser feliz.
You need to be punished.
Debes ser castigado.
Then...
¿Por qué dijiste
why did you say you didn't go?
qué no fuiste?
Right, I shouldn't have gone. I've regretted it thousands of times.
Cierto, no debí haber ido. Me he arrepentido de eso mil veces.
"Why did I go there?
"¿Por qué fui ahí?
Why did I even try to do you a favor?
¿Por qué intenté hacerte un favor?
Was helping you more important than Momyeong?"
¿Era ayudarte más importante que Momyeong?".
I keep asking myself.
No dejo de preguntarme eso.
What happened?
¿Qué pasó en esa cueva?
That guy...
Ese tipo…
Why was he there?
¿Por qué estaba ahí?
He had been imprisoned there.
Lo habían encerrado.
And she happened to be hiding there.
Y ella se escondió ahí.
At first, I didn't know he was that kid.
Al principio, no sabía que era él.
He probably thought I was taking Nak-bin away.
Debió pensar que me llevaría a Nak-bin.
Right at that moment, the King's servants came to get her.
De pronto, los sirvientes del rey llegaron a buscarla.
What are you doing?
¿Qué hacen?
Momyeong...
Momyeong.
Momyeong!
¡Momyeong!
Why...
¿Por qué?
Why have you kept it from me all this time?
¿Por qué no me contaste?
It was the King's order.
El rey lo ordenó.
The King ordered us not to tell anyone about the boy being there.
El rey nos ordenó mantener la existencia del chico en secreto.
As his servants, we had to follow his order.
Como sus sirvientes, teníamos que obedecer.
So, Momyeong died...
Entonces, Momyeong…
because of me.
…murió por mi culpa.
With all due respect, it's no one's fault that Momyeong died.
Con todo respeto, nadie tiene la culpa.
Momyeong and I share one fate since we're twins.
Como gemelos, compartíamos un destino.
One of us was destined to die sooner or later.
Tarde o temprano,
Yes, it's your fault.
Sí, es tu culpa.
I personally don't think you deserve a slap,
No creo que te merezcas una bofetada,
but Biryeom has been wanting to punch you.
pero Biryeom quería golpearte.
Let's go. You were right.
Vamos.
It does feel nice to slap him.
Se sintió bien golpearlo.
Let it go.
Olvídalo.
I know something is weighing on your mind.
Sé que algo te agobia.
You resent Habaek...
Estás resentido con Habaek
and find it hard to forgive Mr. Shin.
y te cuesta perdonar al señor Shin.
And...
Y además
you hate yourself on top of that. It's all because of this, isn't it?
te odias a ti mismo.
-What are you talking about? -You think you ran away.
- ¿De qué hablas? - Sientes que escapaste,
You think you abandoned Momyeong.
que abandonaste a Momyeong.
That's why you can't forgive yourself
Por eso no puedes perdonarte
and hate everything.
y odias todo.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I'm the one who should feel most guilty.
Soy yo quien debería sentirse más culpable.
Don't you think so?
¿No crees?
I told you to run away if you ever saw him.
Te dije que huyeras si lo veías.
The God of Fire?
¿El dios del Fuego?
He should be our blacksmith.
Debería ser nuestro herrero.
Cut it out.
No bromees.
If you ever see him, run as fast as you can.
Si lo llegas a ver, corre lo más rápido que puedas.
He'd definitely be stronger than you.
Es más fuerte que tú.
Did those words...
¿Esas palabras te hicieron retroceder?
-No. -You didn't run away.
- No. - No huiste.
Jingeon dragged you out of there against your will.
Jingeon te sacó a la fuerza.
You don't know anything.
- No sabes nada. - Sin embargo,
part of you wanted to run away.
parte de ti quería huir
Part of you was grateful that Jingeon got you out of there.
y agradeció que Jingeon te sacara de ahí.
Is that what you've been thinking?
¿En eso pensabas?
This is why I always say that you're immature.
Por eso siempre digo que eres inmaduro.
You didn't abandon Momyeong. You saved Jingeon's life.
No abandonaste a Momyeong. Le salvaste la vida a Jingeon.
If something bad happened to you that day,
Si te hubiera pasado algo ese día, Jingeon no estaría vivo hoy.
Do you think the Land of the Sky would've forgiven him?
No lo hubieran perdonado.
Don't take my advice from now on.
Desde ahora, no sigas mis consejos. Siempre pasan cosas así.
And...
Y…
just think of this...
…creo que este es el mayor consuelo que puedo darte.
-Feel better now? -Are you kidding me?
- ¿Te sientes mejor? - ¿Estás bromeando?
He had been imprisoned there.
Lo habían encerrado.
And she happened to be hiding there.
Y ella se escondió ahí.
Mr. Shin.
Señor Shin.
I know that you're here.
Sé que está aquí.
I can feel that you're here.
Puedo sentirlo.
Are we playing hide-and-seek now?
¿Estamos jugando a las escondidas?
I fell.
Me caí.
Is he not here?
¿No está aquí?
That's odd.
Qué raro.
Damn it!
¡Maldición!
He's not like us.
No es como nosotros.
He's not one of them?
¿No es uno de ellos?
Then what is he?
Entonces, ¿qué es?
He's from the world of gods, but he's not a god?
Es del mundo de los dioses, pero ¿no es un dios?
I don't know who my mother is.
No sé quién es mi madre.
My father...
Mi padre…
treated me like a monster.
…me trató como un monstruo.
I wasn't supposed to be born.
Yo no debía nacer.
Disgrace.
Desgracia.
That was my name.
Ese era mi nombre.
My father was afraid people would find out about me,
Mi padre temía que supieran de mí,
so he chose to imprison me for a long time.
así que decidió encerrarme.
The notion of family is different in the divine realm.
La idea de "familia" es diferente en el reino divino.
He said the notion of family is different in the world of gods.
Dijo que la idea de "familia"
Could it be...
¿Podría ser?
No way.
No.
That can't be.
Eso no es posible.
What am I going to do...
¿Qué voy a hacer
when I see him?
cuando lo vea?
Are you going somewhere?
¿Vas a salir?
No.
No.
I'm sorry about last night.
Lamento lo de anoche.
Did something happen?
¿Pasó algo?
No.
No.
-Well... -Yes?
- Bueno… - ¿Sí?
Never mind.
Olvídalo.
Where were you all day?
¿Dónde fuiste hoy?
Did you meet your friends and try to borrow money from them?
¿Les pediste dinero a tus amigos?
The reality must've hit you.
La realidad debe haberte golpeado.
Food.
¡Comida!
You still remember it.
Aún lo recuerdas.
Let's eat something. How about curry?
¿Qué tal si comemos curri?
-What is that? -You'll see. It's yellow.
¿Qué es eso?
I'll go pick up some curry paste.
Pela algunas papas mientras voy a comprar pasta de curri.
Do a good job, okay?
Esfuérzate, ¿sí?
How to peel potatoes.
Cómo pelar papas.
Hello?
¿Aló?
The potatoes are sprouting.
Las papas tienen tantos brotes que se hicieron amigos.
What?
¿Qué?
All right.
Está bien.
Is he addicted to surfing the internet?
¿Lo habrá leído en internet?
Do you have potatoes?
¿Tiene papas?
How ugly.
Qué feo.
HOW TO MAKE CURRY
CÓMO HACER CURRI
Curry...
Curri…
And...
Y también…
I bought the curry paste...
Compré la pasta de curri y las papas.
The curry paste is here. Potatoes and...
Tengo todo aquí.
And bell peppers.
Y pimientos.
HOW TO MAKE CURRY
CÓMO HACER CURRI
Hold on! Calm down.
¡Cálmate!
It's me. You don't recognize me?
Soy yo, ¿no me reconoces?
It's you.
Eres tú.
Yes, I'm the voracious deity, Jugeollin.
Sí, soy Jugeollin, la deidad voraz.
Hold on.
Espera.
Hear me out.
Escúchame.
Hear me out first.
Escúchame primero.
I want you to see Hu-ye.
Quiero que veas a Hu-ye.
Please.
Por favor.
Mr. Shin.
Señor Shin.
-Just a moment. -Let go.
- Espere. - Suélteme.
It's okay.
Está bien.
It's all right.
Todo está bien.
Stay still.
Tranquilo.
It's okay.
Está bien.
-Yun-- -Yes, it's me.
- Yun… - Sí, soy yo.
Where are you?
¿Dónde estás?
-Are you okay? -Yes, I'm fine.
- ¿Estás bien? - Sí, estoy bien.
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
Is it that prick?
¿Es ese imbécil? ¿Estás con él ahora?
Come home now.
Regresa a casa.
I'm totally fine.
Estoy bien.
I'll see you later.
Nos vemos.
Come home now.
Regresa a casa.
You don't even know him.
Ni siquiera lo conoces.
He's not the kind of person you think he is.
No es quien crees que es.
I know him well enough.
Lo conozco bastante bien,
-What? -So don't worry.
- ¿Qué? - así que no te preocupes.
He won't harm me.
No me hará daño. Volveré pronto. No te preocupes.
See?
¿Ves?
She's okay, right?
Está bien, ¿cierto?
You thought he'd harm her? Mr. Shin might be a dangerous man,
¿Ves? El Sr. Shin podrá ser peligroso,
but he'd never harm that girl.
pero nunca la lastimaría.
-She must be at the farm. -Just let him have her.
- Debe estar en la granja. - Déjala.
-That'll be better for her too. -Help me get there.
Será lo mejor para ella.
There is nothing you can do for her.
No puedes hacer nada por ella.
Mr. Shin is very rich.
El señor Shin es muy rico.
It'll take too long by car.
Tardaré mucho en llegar en auto.
-Help me, please. -I don't want to.
Ayúdame.
Mr. Shin.
Señor Shin.
Leave.
Váyase.
-Mr. Shin. -Please!
- Señor Shin. - ¡Por favor!
Leave, please.
Váyase, por favor.
Don't come near me.
No se me acerque.
I destroy everything.
Lo destruyo todo.
If you stay with me...
Si se queda conmigo,
you'll be unhappy.
nunca será feliz.
I almost...
El otro día,
killed you once.
casi la maté.
Some things never change.
Algunas cosas nunca cambian.
Even if you change its appearance,
Aunque se vean diferentes,
it just never changes.
nunca cambian.
No matter how hard you try,
Por mucho que lo intente,
you keep going back.
siempre es lo mismo.
You go back...
Lo mismo,
again and again.
de vuelta al inicio.
where did you begin?
¿Cuál fue su inicio?
Are you trying to say...
¿Intenta decir
that your sins will never disappear?
que sus pecados nunca desaparecerán?
That's right.
Así es.
I am capable of...
Soy capaz de pecar
committing another sin anytime.
en cualquier momento.
-I'll never change. -You're wrong.
- Jamás cambiaré. - Se equivoca.
You're not that kind of person.
No es ese tipo de persona.
"Person"?
¿"Persona"?
Then would you rather be a god?
¿Preferiría ser un dios?
What would you rather be? A god or a human being?
¿Prefiere ser un dios o un humano?
Be a human being.
Sea un humano.
That's better.
Eso es mejor.
A human being...
Ser humano le queda mejor.
You've helped so many people. You've supported so many children.
Ha ayudado a mucha gente y apoyado a muchos niños.
You've helped countless ill people get better.
Ha ayudado a que muchos enfermos se mejoren.
You've saved so many lives.
Ha salvado muchas vidas.
Do you know what you are to those people?
¿Sabe lo que esa gente piensa de usted?
You're like a god to them.
Lo ven como un dios
The work you've done as a human being...
El trabajo que ha hecho como ser humano
was the work of a god.
fue la obra de un dios.
Let's say God is looking down from above.
Si Dios estuviera mirándonos,
He'd see a tiny human being helping other humans
vería a un pequeño ser humano ayudando a otros humanos
in a tiny country, on this tiny planet called Earth.
en un pequeño país, en este pequeño planeta.
God would say, "I'm so busy.
Dios diría: "Estoy tan ocupado.
Thank you for helping me out.
Gracias por ayudarme.
Well done.
Bien hecho.
My blessing upon you."
Bendiciones para ti".
I once told you...
Una vez le dije
that all the trees you planted will become a big forest one day.
que los árboles que planta se convertirán en un bosque.
The life you've been living...
La vida que ha tenido
will never disappear.
nunca desaparecerá.
If you choose to be a human being,
Si elige ser un humano,
I will be...
estaré siempre a su lado.
No matter...
No importa lo que ocurra,
what happens,
siempre estaré a su lado.
I'll be...
Seré…
your god.
…su dios.
But I'm...
Pero soy…
So-a.
So-a.
Let's go.
Vamos.
I'm his psychiatrist.
Soy su psiquiatra.
Is this jealousy?
¿Estás celoso?
I suppose this is better than having no jealousy at all.
Supongo que esto es mejor a que no tengas celos.
But I've never been with a guy who's the jealous type,
Pero nunca he estado con alguien celoso,
so I can't really tell if this is jealousy or not.
así que no sé si son celos o no.
You haven't eaten anything?
¿No comiste nada?
I can tell you're hungry.
Sé que tienes hambre.
It's too late for curry.
Es tarde para el curri,
I'm sorry, but we'll just have to have some cup noodles.
así que hagamos fideos instantáneos.
Wait.
Espera.
-What was that about? -Let's stop there.
- ¿Qué fue eso? - Paremos ahí.
-What? -I said, no more.
- ¿Qué? - Dije que no más.
But why?
Pero ¿por qué?
"Why?"
"¿Por qué?".
Never mind.
Olvídalo.
-Shall we continue? -No.
- ¿Continuamos? - No.
Candy...
Los dulces no se deben comer tan rápido.
-Sorry? -I'll see you tomorrow.
- ¿Qué? - Hasta mañana.
What did he just say?
¿Qué dijo?
What's this about? Is he trying to train me or what?
¿Qué está haciendo? ¿Quiere entrenarme o qué?
He's acting like a total womanizer.
Está actuando como un donjuán.
All right. 10,001, 10,002, 10,003...
Bien. 10 001, 10 002, 10 003…
-Lord Habaek. -Keep going.
- Señor Habaek. - Sigue.
Okay. 10,009, 10,010.
Está bien. 10 009, 10 010.
My Lord, why are you being like this?
Mi señor, ¿por qué actúa así?
This fruit juice quenches thirst like nothing else does.
Este jugo sí que me quita la la sed.
That totally hydrated me.
Me hidrató por completo.
-What was that about? -Let's stop there.
- ¿Qué fue eso? - Paremos ahí.
-What? -I said, no more.
- ¿Qué? - Dije que no más.
But why?
Pero ¿por qué?
Gosh, why on earth did I say that?
Cielos, ¿por qué dije eso?
-What's up? -What?
- ¿Qué pasa? - ¿Qué?
Nothing. Don't mind me.
Nada. Olvídalo.
Why are you all wet?
¿Por qué estás tan mojado?
I'm sweating. It's such a nuisance. I need to use the place called "bathroom."
Estoy sudando. Es una molestia.
What did you say?
¿Qué dijiste?
Why do you need to use my bathroom?
¿Por qué el mío? Tienes tu tina de plástico.
You told me not to sit in it all the time.
Dijiste que no debía usarla tanto.
What? Oh, right.
Cierto.
Well, what I meant was...
Bueno, me refería a que…
Where is it? Upstairs?
¿Dónde está? ¿Arriba?
-What's wrong? -Nothing.
- ¿Qué pasa? - Nada.
I have to go to work.
Debo ir a trabajar.
Really? Then let's come home together later.
Bueno, regresemos juntos más tarde.
What?
¿Qué?
Okay, sure.
Sí, claro.
Gosh, I must be losing my mind.
¿Me estoy volviendo loca?
That man...
Ese hombre…
What the heck did he do to me last night?
¿Qué diablos me hizo anoche?
MR. SHIN HU-YE
SR. SHIN HU-YE
Can we meet briefly?
¿Podemos vernos brevemente?
You should see how your patient is doing after our session, Doctor.
Debería revisar cómo está su paciente, doctora.
PROPOSAL
PROPUESTA
Can you go to Songdo?
¿Puedes ir a Songdo?
They're saying they need me there, but I think you can take care of it.
Creo que puedes encargarte de esto.
-Mr. Kim will fill you in. -Sure.
- El Sr. Kim te ayudará. - Claro.
-What brings you here? -What?
- ¿Qué se te ofrece? - ¿Qué?
If it's about Block World, I have nothing more to tell you.
Si es sobre Block World, no tengo nada más que decir.
You should let your grandfather know.
Deberías avisarle a tu abuelo.
Okay.
Está bien.
But that's not why I'm here. I was just wondering...
Pero no vine por eso.
Are you busy?
¿Está ocupado?
Do you need to talk to Mr. Min?
¿Necesitas hablar con el señor Min?
Yes.
Sí.
You know I called you so many times, right?
Lo llamé varias veces.
-I didn't want to talk to you. -Why not?
- No quería hablar contigo. - ¿Por qué no…
Tell me, Mr. Min.
…señor Min?
-Am I supposed to talk like a counselor? -What? Yes.
- ¿Respondo como consejero? - ¿Qué? Sí.
Are you the one who told Dr. Yun to vacate the office space?
- ¿Hiciste que echaran a la Dra. Yun? - ¿Qué?
Yes. How did you know?
Sí, ¿cómo lo supo?
That's not why I gave you the information.
No te lo conté para que hicieras eso.
How dare you misuse the information? You're shameless.
Qué descarada eres. ¿Cómo te atreves?
"Shameless"?
¿Descarada?
Is that why you're mad at me?
¿Por eso se enojó?
Do you like her too? Is that it?
¿Acaso también le gusta?
I don't like anyone.
No me gusta nadie.
I just want you to become a decent human being.
Solo quiero que seas un ser humano decente.
"A decent human being"?
¿Decente?
Don't contact me until you think you've become a decent human being.
No me contactes hasta que creas que lo eres.
No more counseling for you.
No te aconsejaré más.
I'm busy. I have to go.
Debo irme.
And your plan has failed.
Y tu plan falló.
Become a decent human being?
¿Un ser humano decente?
That jerk!
Ese idiota.
The flowers we planted have already grown this much?
¿Tanto crecieron las flores?
I've been watering them every day.
Las he regado todos los días y las mariposas también les dieron amor.
That's why the flowers could bloom like this.
Por eso crecieron tanto.
Min, you're so smart.
Eres muy inteligente, Min.
Don't grow up too fast.
No crezcas tan rápido
I'll be bored.
o me aburriré.
-I see that you have a guest. -Hello.
Tiene una invitada.
Min, say hi. She's a doctor.
Saluda, Min.
Hello.
Hola.
Yes, hi. You have such a pretty name.
Hola. Qué nombre tan bonito.
Mr. Shin, why is a doctor here?
Señor Shin,
I'm not sick.
No estoy enferma.
-She's here to see me. -Really?
- Vino a verme a mí. - ¿En serio?
Is she Ms. Yun by any chance?
Por casualidad, ¿será la señorita Yun?
I heard you telling someone on the phone that you'll keep your promise
Le dijo a alguien por teléfono que cumpliría su promesa.
and saying, "Yes, Ms. Yun."
Dijo: "Sí, señorita Yun".
I could tell that you were in a really good mood that day.
Estaba de muy buen humor ese día.
-Mr. Shin, you must-- -Min.
Señor Shin, debería…
Oh, is it a secret?
¿Era un secreto?
No, it's not that.
No, no es eso.
Min should leave now.
Vinieron por Min.
She's my neighbor
Es mi vecina
and my only friend.
y mi única amiga.
Her parents passed away, so she lives with her grandmother.
Sus padres fallecieron, así que vive con su abuela.
Her grandmother has to see her doctor twice a month.
Cuando su abuela va al médico,
She always comes with her to get some fresh air and so on.
la deja aquí para que se entretenga.
She can draw very well.
Dibuja muy bien.
I guess she can see everything with her heart.
Supongo que puede ver con su corazón.
Her eyes...
Su ceguera…
It was my doing.
…fue mi culpa.
For a few years after coming here,
Cuando recién llegué aquí,
I didn't know how to control my powers.
no podía controlar mis poderes.
Regardless of my intentions,
Aunque lo intentara,
I had no way of knowing when and what could happen,
no sabía cuándo se iban a manifestar.
so I was always anxious.
Era estresante.
On my first day at the farm,
En mi primer día en la granja,
I saw Min wrapped in a blanket.
vi a Min envuelta en una manta.
When her grandmother stepped out for a brief moment,
Mientras su abuela salió por un rato, un perro salvaje atacó a Min.
I wanted to get the dog off of her,
Quería ahuyentar al perro,
so I used my power.
así que usé mi poder.
The dog died,
El perro murió
and the baby...
y el bebé…
She lost her eyesight.
…perdió la vista.
I think of Min's life...
Vivo mi vida
as my own.
como si fuera la de Min.
Ms. Yun.
Señorita Yun.
-I just made up my mind about something. -Sorry?
- Acabo de decidir algo. - ¿Perdón?
"It won't be a bad idea to just enjoy this regardless of this woman's intentions."
Quizá sea bueno si disfruto esto, independiente de sus intenciones.
What do you mean?
¿Cómo?
Well, you don't need to know the specifics.
No necesita saber los detalles.
Ms. Yun.
Señorita Yun.
Did we perhaps...
Por casualidad, ¿nos habremos conocido antes?
Pardon?
¿Qué?
Well, it just feels like...
Me parece que nos conocimos
a long time ago.
hace mucho tiempo.
It's okay.
Está bien.
It's all right.
Todo está bien.
Stay still.
Tranquilo.
It's okay.
Está bien.
Sir.
Señor.
-We're ready for the meeting. -Okay.
La reunión.
I should go. I'll see you later.
Debo irme. Nos vemos luego.
Okay.
Bien. ¿Qué?
"Later"?
¿"Luego"?
Why is she sleeping when she called me over?
¿Por qué está durmiendo?
Why are you here again?
¿Por qué viniste de nuevo?
What? Me?
¿Qué? ¿Yo?
Yes, you.
Sí, tú.
I'm here for my shift. You told me to just sit here.
Vine por mi turno. Me dijiste que me sentara aquí.
What?
¿Qué?
What did you say?
¿Qué dijiste?
What? Speak louder.
¿Qué? Habla más fuerte.
He is...
Él es…
Yes, go on.
Sí, continúa. ¿De quién hablas?
He's the one who saved me.
…el que me salvó.
It was him.
Fue él.
But...
Pero…
What?
¿Qué?
What are you talking about now?
¿De qué hablas?
I can't hear you!
¡No puedo oírte!
-When did you get here? -A few minutes ago.
- ¿Cuándo llegaste? - Hace poco.
What kind of dream made you that aggressive?
¿Qué estabas soñando?
Gosh, my goodness!
Dios mío.
I saw your landlady in my dream.
Vi a tu casera en mi sueño.
Why does she have to brag about her boyfriend even in my dream?
¿Por qué debe presumir de su novio incluso en mis sueños?
-What? -I can't believe this.
- ¿Qué? - No puedo creerlo.
She's making me feel upset about the fact that I'm single.
Me hace sentir mal por estar soltera.
I was even going to do a reading for her, thinking it might be a bad omen.
Le iba a leer el futuro pensando que era un mal presagio.
I can't believe she was bragging about some man saving her life.
No puedo creer que presumiera de que un hombre le salvó la vida.
But you must really be helping me boost my psychic powers.
Debes estar ayudándome a aumentar mis poderes psíquicos.
I can hear things again.
Puedo oír cosas otra vez.
Oh, right. The new owner of the building will stop by later today.
El nuevo dueño del edificio pasará por acá.
Really? It's so messy here, though.
¿En serio? Pero está tan desordenado.
-Do we have anything to give him? -I'll go buy some cold drinks.
- ¿Tenemos algo para ofrecerle? - Compraré bebidas frías.
Hey, Hyeong-sik.
Hola, Hyeong-sik.
Why are you crying?
¿Por qué lloras?
What? Your appendix burst?
¿Qué? ¿Apendicitis?
Yes, okay. I'll leave right now.
Sí, está bien.
Which hospital are you at?
¿En qué hospital estás?
Hey.
¡Oye!
Jeez, that slacker.
Cielos, ese holgazán.
Why make such a fuss about appendicitis? My goodness.
Cielos, ¿por qué tanto alboroto por una apendicitis?
He's useless.
Es un inútil.
Is this the only rag we have?
¿Es el único trapo que tenemos?
I wonder if he's on his way here.
¿Vendrá de vuelta ya?
I should ask him if he can bring some rags.
Le pediré que traiga más trapos.
What's wrong with me?
¿Qué me está pasando?
WATER DEMON
DEMONIO DEL AGUA
MY SERVANT
SIRVIENTA
What happened to your face?
¿Y esa cara?
Oh, well...
Bueno…
I just did it for fun.
Solo estaba jugando.
What?
¿Qué?
No, it's nothing.
No es nada.
Do you find me attractive?
¿Te gusto?
Well...
Bueno…
Can you bring a few rags when you're coming?
¿Puedes traer algunos trapos cuando vengas?
Am I attractive or not?
¿Te gusto o no?
-My gosh, I have to go! -Hey, what's wrong?
- Cielos, ¡tengo que irme! - ¿Qué pasa?
Gosh, what did this guy...
Dios mío,
do to me last night?
¿qué me hizo anoche?
I must be possessed by some dirty-minded evil spirit.
Debo estar poseída por un espíritu indecente.
Why does she keep losing her mind?
¿Por qué sigue perdiendo la cabeza?
How dare she order me to bring rags...
¿Cómo se atreve a pedirme que le lleve trapos?
Hey.
Oye.
How did you get in here?
¿Cómo entraste?
Don't you think that question is a little weird?
¿Qué tipo de pregunta es esa?
I can go anywhere. I'm a god.
Puedo ir a cualquier lado. Soy un dios.
I didn't want to see you either.
Yo tampoco quería verte. Mura insistió en que viniera.
She told me to hear what you have to say.
Dijo que debía escucharte.
-How's Jingeon? -He's fine.
- ¿Y Jingeon? - Está bien.
No matter what he says,
No importa lo que diga,
it is my fault that Momyeong died.
Momyeong murió por mi culpa.
I caused his death.
Yo provoqué su muerte.
But I've been living...
Pero he vivido
without knowing that he died because of me.
sin saber que murió por mi culpa.
That's why you're so angry.
Por eso estás tan enojado.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
This is what Mura wanted you...
Eso es lo que Mura quería
to hear from me, right?
que te dijera.
He was probably...
Probablemente,
trying to protect Nak-bin.
quiso proteger a Nak-bin.
It must've been his first time seeing a female human after many years.
Debió ser la primera humana que veía en años.
I can't think that far yet. I need some time.
No puedo pensar en eso aún. Necesito tiempo.
Wait.
Espera.
Didn't he ask you for money with this kind of face?
¿No intentó pedirte dinero?
-He did. -He did?
- Sí. - ¿En serio?
-So? -I told him that no one
- ¿Y qué hiciste? - Le dije que ya nadie usa efectivo.
-And? -"Then give me your credit card.
- ¿Y? - Me pidió mi tarjeta
If you don't have one, give me some diamonds.
o que le diera diamantes.
When I refused, he said, "This is the King's order."
Cuando me negué, dijo que era una orden del rey.
I'm speechless. Make sure you never give him any money.
Qué atrevido. No le des nada.
Why don't you stop doing favors for him?
Tú lo sigues ayudando.
You said you weren't going to take him to the farm, but you did.
Lo terminaste llevando a la granja.
No more favors for him.
No le haré más favores. Lo ignoraré para que regrese pronto.
What?
¿Qué?
Can I kiss you?
- ¿Puedo besarte? - ¿Te congelo la lengua?
All right. Do you want to take it to the next level when we get home?
Bien, pero ¿quieres hacer otras cosas en casa?
Should I tell him not to come?
¿Le digo que no venga?
I'll tell him not to come today.
Le diré que no venga hoy.
We can go home together starting tomorrow. My gosh!
Lo pospondré para mañana.
NURSE YU
ENFERMERO YU
Hyeong-sik is fine.
Hyeong-sik está bien.
As for picking up drinks for the new landlord...
Y sobre las bebidas para el dueño…
Jeez, that slacker!
Este holgazán.
Gosh, I'm getting a headache.
Me duele la cabeza.
What? "Bring some rags"?
¿Quería algunos trapos?
Who does she think I am?
¿Quién se cree que soy?
-What are you doing here? -Hello, how have you been?
- ¿Qué haces aquí? - ¿Cómo estás?
That's none of your business.
No es asunto tuyo.
Why are you here?
¿Qué haces aquí?
-I came to say hello as the new landlord. -"Landlord"?
Soy el nuevo dueño.
What's that?
¿Qué es eso?
You don't need to know. They say landlords are above God.
Dicen que los dueños están por encima de Dios.
Landlords can be quite powerful at times.
Podemos ser muy poderosos a veces.
I don't give a shit. Just get lost.
No me importa. Solo lárgate.
I've already said this to Ms. Yun,
Ya le dije esto a la señorita Yun,
but I'll say it again.
pero lo diré de nuevo.
You see, what I'm best at
Lo que mejor hago es esperar.
No one can defy time and gravity.
Nadie puede vencer al tiempo y la gravedad.
You have to return to the divine realm eventually,
Debes regresar al reino divino,
but I'll still be living here with her.
pero yo seguiré viviendo aquí con ella.
So?
¿Sí?
I'll do all the things that you'll never be able
Haré todas las cosas que nunca podrás hacer con ella.
Thankfully,
Afortunadamente, tengo mucho que ofrecer.
What did you say?
¿Qué dijiste?
Excuse me, guys.
Disculpen.
What brings you here? You don't have an appointment today.
¿Por qué vino? No estaba citado para hoy.
-I thought you knew that I was coming. -What?
- ¿No le avisaron que vendría? - ¿Qué?
You didn't mention anything when I saw you earlier.
- No dijo nada cuando nos vimos. - No digas nada.
Don't talk to him.
No le hables.
Lock the door and leave the key under the flower pot.
Cierra la puerta y deja la llave bajo la maceta.
Calm down, will you? I'm worried we might get into an accident.
Cálmate, no quiero que choquemos.
Is this also jealousy?
¿Estás celoso?
This does feel more like jealousy than what you did yesterday.
Pareces más celoso que ayer.
Anyway, you're charming even when you're jealous.
Eres encantador, incluso cuando estás celoso.
You're charming even when you're angry.
Incluso cuando estás enojado.
-Where are we going? -I don't know.
- ¿Adónde vamos? - No lo sé.
Do you want to go see the sunset?
¿Veamos el atardecer?
Let's hurry. Who knows when someone else will show up and bother us?
Vamos rápido. Antes de que alguien nos moleste.
Come on. Let's go.
Vamos.
Over there. The sun will set in that direction.
El sol se ocultará por ahí.
Let's watch from here.
Sentémonos aquí.
This is such a memorable image. It's the perfect way to end the day.
Qué imagen más perfecta para terminar el día.
I guess this is why people purposely go see the sunset even when they're busy.
Supongo que por esto la gente viene a ver el atardecer.
To tell you the truth,
A decir verdad,
I came here once with my parents when I was young.
una vez vine aquí con mis padres cuando era joven.
Back then, I didn't get this kind of feeling.
Pero en ese entonces, no tuve esta sensación.
My dad kept worrying...
Mi papá estaba preocupado
about the kids we left at home,
por los niños que dejamos en casa,
and my mom was mad at him for being like that.
y mi mamá estaba molesta con él por ser así.
They kept arguing nonstop, and I was on pins and needles.
Discutieron tanto que me puse ansiosa.
So we just had a bowl of clam noodles and went home.
Tomamos sopa de almejas y nos fuimos.
What are you thinking?
¿En qué piensas?
Tomorrow,
En el mañana
the day after tomorrow,
y el día siguiente
and the day after that.
y el siguiente.
Your future without me.
En tu futuro sin mí.
Let's only think about today.
Hablemos del presente.
You said something very impressive a little while ago.
Hace un tiempo dijiste algo muy bonito.
You told me about those who believe
Hablaste sobre la gente
they can live the rest of their lives with their memories of today.
que vive su vida con los recuerdos van juntando.
I said that?
¿Yo dije eso?
When?
¿Cuándo?
A while ago.
Hace un tiempo.
When something fades in the sun, it becomes history.
Lo que se oculta con el sol, se convierte en historia.
And when something soaks up the moonlight,
Y lo que absorbe la luz de la luna,
it becomes a myth.
se convierte en un mito.
That means our story...
Así que que nuestra historia
will become a myth.
se convertirá en un mito.
-I've received the message. -Please get ready, Lord Habaek.
- Recibí el mensaje. - Prepárese, señor Habaek.
Can I be greedy?
¿Puedo ser ambiciosa?
Let me say this just in case. You know what will happen if you don't return?
Solo por si acaso, ¿sabes lo que pasará si no regresas?
-Let's stay together. -All right.
- Sigamos juntos. - Está bien.
Habaek will perish if he doesn't ascend the throne.
Habaek morirá si no asciende al trono.
I don't want that kind of tragedy.
No quiero esa tragedia.
Try your best not to be lonely for as long as you can.
Intenta no sentirte sola.
Can you live without him?
¿Podrás vivir sin él?
Then let me tell you something you don't know.
Pues déjame decirte algo que no sabes.
He's the one who saved me.
Él fue el que me salvó.
-It means you're going to die. -But the person who saved me...
- Significa que morirás. - Pero la persona que me salvó…